welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using kdenlive the free video
使用kdenlive免费视频的教程
editing software in this video we're
在这段视频中编辑软件我们正在
going to be adding in a video clip that
我将在一段视频剪辑中添加
has existing audio and will be swapping
已有音频 并将交换
out the audio from that video and just
从那段视频中取出音频 然后
adding in music instead of the audio
添加音乐而不是音频
that the video came with so if you want
所以如果你想要的话
to follow along I'm just gonna be
为了跟随我 我只会成为
downloading some project clips from
从以下位置下载一些项目剪辑
pixabay and from freesound.org the pics
Pixabay和来自freesound.org的图片
of a clip we're going to find first of
我们首先要找到的一段视频
all I'm gonna change my search to videos
我只会把我的搜索改成视频
and I'll search for this video called
我会搜索这段名为
runoff I'm thinking rain and runoff at
径流我认为降雨和径流在
the same time it's just a video of rain
与此同时 这只是一段下雨的视频
falling against a window so I left click
摔倒在窗户上 所以我点击了一下
on this it's what it sounds like it's
在这件事上 它就像它听起来那样
just some raindrops dripping down some
只是一些雨点滴落在一些
glass so we'll download this video click
玻璃 所以我们将下载这个视频点击
free download I already have it
免费下载我已经有了
downloaded I think I did the 1920 by
我想我是在1920年前下载的
1080 go ahead and download and download
1080继续下载和下载
this video and then I'm going to also be
这个视频 然后我也将成为
using going to freesound.org I just
使用Going to freesound.org 我只是
searched music and this search might
搜索音乐 此搜索可能
change at the time that you surged up
在你高涨的时候改变
with different options here but today I
有不同的选择 但今天我
was able to just find this music here
能够在这里找到这首音乐
play this show is kind of the wave form
播放这部剧是一种波形
of it
其中之一
I'll left-click on this file and this
我将左键单击此文件和此文件
files by JP music 82 and the last one
JP MUSIC 82的文件和最后一个
was from most media both of them are
来自大多数媒体 他们两人都是
really released under the Creative
真的在Creative下发布
Commons Ebro license so we really
Commons Ebro许可证 所以我们真的
appreciate these users sharing these
感谢这些分享这些内容的用户
files with us go ahead and just hit
与我们的文件继续 只是点击
download and you can download this I
下载 你可以下载这个I
already have it downloaded so they are
已经下载了 所以他们
in my downloads folder and then to bring
在我的下载文件夹中 然后带到
those in we can just click here we've
我们只需点击此处即可
done before you can go clip I mean that
在你可以去剪之前做好 我是说
project add clip or you can just click
项目添加剪辑或您只需单击
on this under your project bin you can
在你的项目垃圾箱下面 你可以
click on this add clip button and it
点击此添加剪辑按钮 它将
brings up a dialog to add the clip in so
弹出一个对话框以在其中添加剪辑
maybe we'll add the mp3 file the music
也许我们会把mp3文件加到音乐里
file this way and hit OK and now we have
这样归档 然后点击OK 现在我们就有了
our music file but you can also drag and
我们的音乐文件 但您也可以拖动和
drop so if you have your doc your your
放下 这样如果你有你的医生你的
folder open or your files you're viewing
打开文件夹或您正在查看的文件
them in the browser here come back we'll
他们在这里的浏览器 回来 我们将
just drag and drop this video of the
只需将这段视频拖放到
rain runoff into our project bin
雨水径流进入我们的工程垃圾箱
remember we always have to have it in
记住 我们总是要把它放在里面
the project bin if we try to drag it
如果我们试图将它拖到项目垃圾箱
down to the timeline it won't work
精确到时间线 它不会起作用
nothing will go into the timeline unless
任何事情都不会进入时间线 除非
it's first in our project bin and so
它是我们项目垃圾箱中的第一个 所以
from our project bin we can kind of
从我们的项目垃圾箱中 我们可以
scroll this over and see I rearranged
将这个滚动到上面 可以看到我重新排列了
this since the last video and so if we
这是从上一段视频开始的 所以如果我们
can actually click and drag different
可以实际点击并拖动不同的
parts to anywhere we want to but I'm
去任何我们想去的地方 但我
gonna keep my project bin right here
我要把我的项目垃圾箱放在这里
right there so if yours looks a little
就在那里 所以如果你的看起来有点
different than mine you can rearrange it
和我的不同 你可以重新安排
and look I actually opened up a third
你看 我实际上开了第三家
window now oh I have clip properties now
窗口现在哦 我现在有剪辑属性了
as a separate thing and it was a little
作为一件独立的事情 这是一种
tab down here so we'll we'll keep it
把标签放在这里 这样我们就会把它留着
there as a tab so what that does it just
有一个选项卡 所以它的作用是什么
creates a tab at the bottom that we can
在底部创建一个选项卡 我们可以
toggle between just like we were with
切换 就像我们在
our project monitor and clip monitor and
我们的项目监视器和剪辑监视器和
we can watch our runoff see what this
我们可以看我们的决选看看这是什么
video looks like awesome so to get
视频看起来很棒 所以
started we need to put it down into our
开始 我们需要把它放到我们的
into our timeline
进入我们的时间线
so I'll left click on this video file
所以我会左键点击这个视频文件
and I'll move it to video 1 track and
我会把它移到视频1音轨上
then our audio file I'll left-click on
然后我将左键点击我们的音频文件
and put it on to the audio audio one
并把它放到音频设备上
track so now we have these I want to
所以现在我们有了这些 我想
zoom in and see them a little bit closer
放大一点 近距离地看他们
so I'm gonna come to the bottom right
所以我要走到右下角
here and just with the scroll bar scroll
在这里 仅使用滚动条滚动
in to zoom in so I can see it a little
放大 这样我就能看到它了
bit better now I can click if I hold and
现在好一点了 如果我按住并点击
hold down on my left mouse cursor I can
按住我的鼠标左键 我可以
actually it's called scrubbing I can
实际上 这叫擦洗 我可以
scrub along and watch the video and
边走边看视频 然后
listen to the audio and so I don't do
听音频 所以我不会这样做
too much of that because I'm recording
太多了 因为我在录制
the video at the same time my computer
视频同时出现在我的电脑上
is getting a little overloaded I think
我觉得有点超负荷了
anyway and then um I want to get rid of
不管怎样 然后 嗯 我想摆脱
some of these video tracks we have three
其中一些视频曲目我们有三个
video tracks you don't have to do this
录像带 你不必这么做
but it's just something nice to learn
但这只是一件值得学习的好事情
how to do if you right click on a video
如果你用鼠标右键点击视频该怎么办
track you can just go to delete track it
曲目你只需去删除曲目就可以了
says what do you want to do with delete
表示您要如何处理删除
video 3 ok video 2 right click delete
视频3确定视频2右击删除
track and ok so now we just have one
轨道和好的 所以现在我们只有一个
video track and I'm gonna leave our
录像带 我要离开我们的
second audio track and I'll show you why
第二首音轨 我会告诉你为什么
in a second here yeah but we can zoom in
在这里的一秒钟内是的但是我们可以放大
and make our tracks are kind of thin now
让我们的足迹变得稀薄
we can make them even thinner by
我们可以让它们变得更薄
clicking this button here or this one
点击此处或此按钮
smaller tracks makes them small so you
较小的轨道使它们变得较小 因此您
can have a dozen different video tracks
可以有十几个不同的视频曲目
and audio tracks and have a very complex
和音轨 并且有一个非常复杂的
edit that you're doing or if it's a
编辑您正在进行的操作 或者如果它是
simple one like this we can just click
像这样简单的一个 我们只需点击
and scale it up and make it a little bit
把它放大 让它变得有点
larger to see
大图可见
so you see we see we have our audio
所以你看 我们有我们的音频
waveform down here for our music and
在这里为我们的音乐和
then there's also a little bit of audio
然后还有一小段音频
you see these kind of almost looks like
你看这些看起来就像是
a little mountain ridges that we're
一座小小的山脊 我们正在
seeing the audio waveform of the video
查看视频的音频波形
as well if we want a mute we can click
同样 如果我们想要静音 可以点击
this speaker button and it'll mute just
这个扬声器按钮 它会静音
that track so audio one track is now
这首曲子现在是音频一首曲目
muted now if we go ahead and play this
现在静音 如果我们继续播放这个
we just hear the rain if I click unmute
如果我点击取消静音 我们只会听到雨声
that's music to start playing and we can
这是开始播放的音乐 我们可以
go back and use just the RAM so it's
回去只使用内存 这样它就
just music playing both of them and have
只是播放他们两个人的音乐 并有
just the video playing so that's that's
只是在播放视频 所以就是这样
how you can control muting this lock
如何控制将此锁定静音
button makes it so when it's locked
当按钮被锁定时 它会这样
we can't edit or make any changes to it
我们不能对其进行编辑或任何更改
whereas this one we can still move
而这一次我们仍然可以移动
around the audio we can move it down to
围绕音频 我们可以将其向下移动到
audio to if we want but this lock button
如果我们想要音频 只需按下此锁定按钮
makes this track the watch so that's
使这条轨迹成为手表 所以这是
what those buttons do well I'm going to
这些按钮做得很好 我要去
umm you both of these now and I'm going
嗯 你们俩现在一起去 我要走了
to show you how to separate out the
来向您展示如何将
audio so we could just mute it and then
音频 这样我们就可以静音 然后
we could render our video and be fine
我们可以呈现我们的视频 然后就可以了
but sometimes you might want to separate
但有时你可能想分开
the audio from your video and use just
视频中的音频 只需使用
the audio file somewhere or you might
音频文件在某个地方 或者您可能
want to move it forward since this is a
我想把它向前推进 因为这是一个
rain sound it does not really doesn't
雨声它不是真的不是
matter if it's tied to a specific event
重要的是它是否与特定的事件捆绑在一起
of this video because it's just a
因为这只是一个
constant pattern the whole time so we
一成不变的模式 所以我们
might want to move it forward or back a
可能希望将其向前或向后移动一个
little bit so let's right-click and go
有一点 所以让我们右击并开始
to split audio and that puts the audio
分割音频 这样就把音频
down in this audio track below they're
在下面的音轨里 他们是
still tied to each other they're still
他们仍然紧紧地绑在一起
it's called grouped they're grouped
这叫分组 他们是分组的
together so if we move one the other one
所以如果我们把一个移动到另一个
will move along with it that's because
会随波逐流 那是因为
if you ever have like a person a video
如果你有过像一个人这样的视频
of a person talking or something that
一个人在说话 或者其他什么东西
you want a lot of times your audio will
你想要很多次你的音频将
be you'll want it to be in sync with
是你想要它与之同步
your video but at this we don't want
你的视频 但现在我们不想
that to happen in this case necessarily
在这种情况下必然会发生这种情况
so we can right click and go to ungroup
因此 我们可以右键单击并转到解组
Clips and that'll make it so that we can
夹子 这样我们就可以
control you separately we could do the
单独控制你 我们可以做
same thing if we want this music maybe
同样的 如果我们想要这首音乐
we want this to go to the end here and
我们希望这件事能在这里结束
we want this music track and this video
我们想要这首音乐曲目和这盘录像带
track to go together we can we can hold
走在一起的轨道我们可以我们可以坚持
down the shift key and select both of
按住Shift键并同时选择
them or maybe the control keys edit yeah
它们或者可能是控制键编辑是的
hold down the control key we
按住Ctrl键我们
select them both and move them together
同时选中它们并将它们移动到一起
like that and we can hold down the
就像这样 我们就可以按住
control key once they're both selected
Ctrl键 一旦它们都被选中
we can right click and go group clips
我们可以右键单击并转到组剪辑
then they'll always stay together even
那么他们将永远在一起 即使是
if we don't even if we unclick but I'm
如果我们没有 即使我们取消点击 但我
gonna ungroup them so that's how
我要把他们分开 这样就可以了
grouping works I wanted to show you that
分组作品我想给你们看的是
real quick Oh
很快哦
today ungroup um yeah another one group
今天解组 嗯 是的 另一个组
okay so let's do this let's have the
好的 让我们开始吧 让我们有
rain sound start with a black screen and
雨声从黑屏开始
then let's have our video start so it's
那么让我们开始我们的视频吧 所以
gonna go left to right the playhead is
从左到右 播放头是
gonna start over here we'll have some
从这里开始 我们会有一些
rain and the video will start maybe we
下雨了 录像带就要开始了 也许我们
want to end the whole thing we want this
想要结束这一切我们想要这一切
music to end with the last frame of the
以最后一帧结束的音乐
video clip so to do that we're going to
因此 为了做到这一点 我们将
cut the video like we did in the last
像我们上一次那样剪裁视频
the last tutorial we go over here to
我们在这里介绍的最后一个教程
this little scissor icon and left-click
这个小剪刀图标 然后左键点击
it the scripts our razor tool and we are
脚本是我们的剃须刀工具 而我们
cursor turns to a little scissors and
光标变成一把小剪刀
wherever we click we can cut I'm just
无论我们点击哪里 我们都可以切入 我只是
left clicking a couple times we can cut
左键点击几次 我们就可以切到
different parts of this and if you want
不同的部分 如果你想
to move and we have to go back to our
才能搬家 我们必须回到我们的
selection tool which is right here and
选择工具 就在这里
we can select and grab this piece of
我们可以选择和抓住这块
audio around and move it we don't want
我们不想要的音频和移动它
in the video track necessarily but we
在视频轨道上是必然的 但我们
hit the Delete key and it goes away so
按Delete键 它就会消失
we'll select this one left click and
我们将选择此鼠标左键单击并
delete left click and delete and then we
删除左键点击并删除 然后我们
let's go back to our razor tool or we
让我们回到我们的剃须刀工具 否则我们
gonna hit the X key on our keyboard to
我要按键盘上的X键来
bring up that razor tool and then we go
拿起剃须刀 然后我们就走
right to where the playhead is because I
就在播放头的位置 因为我
want to cut this right at the right when
我想把这个从右边剪下来
our video clip ends I want the audio to
我们的视频片段结束了 我想让音频
end as well and then to get back to our
也结束了 然后回到我们的
selection tool we can click here or we
选择工具 我们可以单击此处或我们
can press the S key on our keyboard and
可以按我们键盘上的S键 然后
left-click it's swept it has the red box
左键单击它已扫描 它有一个红色方框
around it hit delete and so now our
在它周围点击删除 所以现在我们的
video and our music will end at the same
视频和我们的音乐将以同样的方式结束
time and then just at the start of the
时间 然后在开始的时候
video it's gonna be all black but maybe
视频它将是一片漆黑 但也许
I kind of want that as like an effect
我有点想让它成为一种效果
and so I'm not gonna do any more in this
所以我不会再做更多的事情了
video but in the next video we'll be
视频 但在下一个视频中我们将
we'll look at actually adding in these
我们将看到实际上添加了这些
effects here so you just like left click
效果在这里 所以你只需点击鼠标左键
and drag and drop an audio effect in and
并将音频效果拖放到和
then it actually adds in that audio
然后它实际上添加了音频
effect
效应
to that part of the file and same with
添加到文件的该部分 并与
the video effects so we'll be playing
视频特效 所以我们将播放
with a lot of these different things in
有很多这些不同的东西
the future in future tutorials so check
未来教程中的未来 因此请查看
those out but to render this video out
但要把这段视频渲染出来
so I'm gonna delete these effects that I
所以我要删除这些影响 我
put in and how I should have done that
以及我应该怎么做
yet and to render this project out we'll
为了完成这个项目 我们将
just go left click render if we like it
如果我们喜欢 只需左键点击渲染即可
the way it is I always click on mp4 and
我总是点击MP4 然后
then choose a location to render this
然后选择一个位置来渲染它
file to so I'm gonna do mine on my
所以我要在我的
desktop I'll just call it test mp4 and
桌面我就叫它测试MP4和
hit save then we just hit render to file
点击保存 然后我们只点击渲染到文件
it goes since the short video it's 11
从短视频到现在是11点
seconds long but little over 11 seconds
几秒长 但11秒多一点
it just takes a few seconds to render
只需几秒钟即可进行渲染
and then we have this rendering of this
然后我们有了这个的渲染
video and again if you're making an
视频 如果你正在制作一部
actual real project you might want to
实际的实际项目 您可能想要
check out make you want to make sure you
结账让你想要确保你
go into your project and and project
进入你的项目和和项目
settings and you can configure the type
设置 并且您可以配置类型
of video you want if you're working in
如果您在中工作
4k if you're working in 1080p 720p
4K 如果您在1080p 720p下工作
that's just the size the resolution but
这只是分辨率的大小 但是
by default I think I'm not sure if it's
默认情况下 我想我不确定它是否
defaulter I set it but I always work in
我设置了它 但我总是在
1080p and 30 FPS or 29.97 fps
1080p和30 fps或29.97 fps
anyway that's completely rendered out
不管怎么说 这已经完全呈现出来了
now so we'll just see our finished
现在 我们将看到我们完成了
product this is our video that we made
产品这是我们制作的视频
and pretty awesome so thanks for
而且非常棒 所以谢谢你
watching this video join me in the next
观看这段视频和我一起参加下一场比赛
one where we'll dive into using some of
在这个主题中 我们将使用一些
these different effects go ahead and
这些不同的效果继续下去
like the subscribe comment below and
喜欢下面的订阅评论和
we'll see you in the next one
我们会在下一节见到你